[First, "My Amanto Idea" contest. The winner is Noriko Mach.]
[Gintoki tripped on his scooter in the opening and brought it to Gengai for repair...]
(銀時)おう おう おう！
きれいに直ってるじゃねえか！
Oh, you fixed it up good as new.
すっげぇな おい！
(源外)あたりめぇよ！
You're amazing.
Piece o' cake!
[Mechanic's Shop]
ｵﾚを誰だと思ってるんだ！
指名手配犯｡
Who do you think I am?
A wanted criminal.
ｵﾒｴ 人の傷口ほじくって
楽しいか？
You enjoy pecking at a man's wounds, huh?
冗談だよ！ ほら ﾊﾞｲｸの傷口を
ほじくってくれた お礼にさ➡
I'm just kidding.
I'm getting you back for pecking at my scooter's wounds.
ｵﾚも ｱﾝﾀの傷口を…｡
ほじらんでも ええわい！
Thought I'd dig into your wounds too...
I was repairing it!!
ありがとよ じいさん！
Thanks a lot, old man.
Just the kind of work I'd expect from Edo's number one mechanic, Gengai Hiraga.
さすが 江戸一番の からくり技師
平賀 源外だ｡
I'm glad you realize that.
わかりゃいいんだよ｡
で 金のことなんだがな…｡
So about the payment...
また なんかあったら
よろしくﾒｶﾄﾞｯｸな！
Well, if anything pops up again, I'll be counting on you, Doc. Mechanics.
[Note: Spoof of manga Yoroshiku Mechadoc (Mechanical Doctor).]
あっ いや 金のことなんだがな｡
Now about the bill...
じゃあな！
いや 金！
See'ya.
Um...the bill...
あぁ～あ…｡
ん？ うごぉ～!? ｼﾞｼﾞｲ
ﾃﾒｴ 細工してやがったな！
Damn you, old man!
You tampered with it, didn't you?
(源外)ﾌﾝ！ 金の切れ目が
縁の切れ目だ｡
When the money gives out, so does the love.
おりゃりゃりゃ!?
(２人)ん!?
うわぁ～!!
おい！ 大丈夫か!?
Hey! You all right?
What the hell are you doing, involving innocent bystanders?
(源外)おい 一般人に
迷惑かけるﾔﾂがあるか！
ﾃﾒｴが 車輪に
細工なんかしなきゃ➡
If you hadn't booby-trapped my tire, this wouldn't have happened!
こんなことには
ならなかったんだよ！
You okay, Miss?
大丈夫か？ ねえちゃん！
(のり子)大丈夫です｡
I'm fine.
(のり子)ちょっと
転んだだけなんで…｡
It was a minor collision.
You're fine?!
大丈夫です って
血だらけだぞ おい！
But you're covered with blood!
No, I'm really okay.
いや ﾎﾝﾄ大丈夫です！
私 ﾎﾝﾄ ちょっと➡
I really do need to keep going.
行かなきゃﾀﾞﾒなんで！
(源外)どこへ!? ﾑﾘ ﾑﾘ ﾑﾘ ﾑﾘ！
Going where?
Are you nuts?! No way, no way!
違うとこ行っちまうぞ！
(のり子)うぅ!?
The only place you're going is to the morgue!!
おい!?
(源外)しっかりしろ！
Hang in there!
ﾊﾞｲｸを… 早く私にﾊﾞｲｸを…！
My scooter...
Just hurry up and give me a scooter.
私 走り続けないと➡
I...If I don't keep riding... If I can't feel the wind...
風を感じないと
死んじゃう… うぐ！
I'll die...
あぁ…｡
What's with her?
何だ？ ｺｲﾂ…｡
["For the Wind Is the Life"]
(源外)魔破 のり子｡ 快速星出身
職業 飛脚か…｡
Noriko Mach.
Born on Planet Highspeed.
Occupation: Express Messenger.
ｳﾜｻには聞いたことがあったが➡
I've heard rumors about them, but I had no idea such an obnoxious clan actually existed.
こんな厄介な種族が
ﾎﾝﾄに いたとはな…｡
そんな言い方 やめてください！
Don't talk about us like that.
We are the noble people of the wind. We're honorable wind spirits!
私たちは 風の精霊とも言われる
由緒正しき風の民なんです！
いつも風をまとっていないと
身を保てない繊細な➡
We are delicate, nymph-like beings that have to
ﾎﾝﾄ もう ほとんど妖精みたいな
可憐な種族なんです｡
feel the wind at all times or we lose our bodies.
要するに なに？
いっつも走ってないと➡
So what are you saying?
That you have to keep running all the time?!
ﾀﾞﾒってこと？
常に泳いでねえと死んじまう➡
Kinda like sharks that die if they're not constantly swimming?
ｻﾒみたいな連中ってこと？
いえ ﾊﾞｲｸとか➡
No, as long as we're riding any form of locomotion like a scooter that allows us to feel the wind.
特に風を浴びれる乗り物に
乗っていれば なんとか…｡
Running on my own is a bit tiring.
自分の足で走るのは
あのﾀﾙいんで…｡
じゃあ ﾃﾒｴで走れや！ なんでｵﾚが
ﾊﾞｲｸ役やらなきゃいけねえの！
Go run on your own!
Why the hell do I have to be your scooter?
(のり子)ぐっ… 苦しい！
すみません もうちょっとｽﾋﾟｰﾄﾞを！
I...I'm in pain.
I'm sorry, but can you go a little faster?
誰が いちばん苦しいと
思ってるんだ!?
Who do you think is in the most pain here?
We can't make an injured girl run.
手負いの女 走らせるわけには
いかねえだろ！
もうちょっとで ﾊﾞｲｸも直るからよ｡
I'm almost done fixing your scooter.
I'm sorry for causing trouble.
ごめんなさい 迷惑おかけして…｡
Since I can't do anything, I'll sing "Sarai."
[Note: A famous song written for the TV show "24 hour TV, Love will Save the Earth." It lasts 24 hours and the song is sung at the end.]
私 何もできないから
『ｻﾗｲ』歌います｡
24時間 走れってか!?
So you want me to keep running for 24 hours?
Um, could you fix that piece of junk later and repair mine first?
(のり子)あの そのｵﾝﾎﾞﾛﾊﾞｲｸは
後にして➡
先に私のﾊﾞｲｸを
直してくれませんか？
私 仕事が…｡
おい ｵﾝﾎﾞﾛﾊﾞｲｸって何だよ！
I have to go to work...
Hey, what do you mean, "piece of junk"?
(源外)ｵﾒｴのﾊﾞｲｸ 大破しちまって
時間が かかる｡
Your scooter was seriously wrecked, so it's going to take longer to fix.
代わりに ｺｲﾂのに乗っていけ！
Why don't you take his scooter instead?
お～い 代わりって何だよ!?
それ ｵﾚのなんですけど！
What do you mean, "instead"?
That's my scooter, you know.
だが ｵﾒｴ
そのｹｶﾞでﾊﾞｲｸなんて乗れるのか？
But can you ride a scooter with those injuries?
(のり子)乗れます！
郵便受けの向こうで➡
Yes, I can.
There are people waiting for me to deliver their packages.
私を待ってくれている
人たちがいるんです！
Besides, this is my first job on Earth.
それに 実は
これが地球での初仕事なんです｡
こんな私じゃ
まともに働けるところがなくて➡
Someone like me can't get a decent job.
もう私には ここしかないんです！
This is the only thing I can do.
私 絶対 負けられないんです｡
I have to make this work!
宇宙一の飛脚になるって
心に決めたんです！
I swore to myself that I would become the best express messenger in the entire cosmos!
下ろしてください！
Please put me down!
I don't have time to be fooling around here.
私は こんなところで
ﾓﾀﾓﾀしている暇は ないんです！
ｵﾒｴが おぶってくれって
言ったんだろうが！
You're the one who wanted the piggyback ride.
あなたたちみたいな暇人に
つきあってる暇はないんです！
I don't have time to hang out with slackers like you!
早く下ろしてって… うがぁ～!!
Hurry, let me down-
(のり子)すみません…｡
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to make you help me with my job, too...
仕事の手伝いまで
させることになっちゃって…｡
もういいよ｡ もとはといえば
ｵﾚの責任だしな｡
That's okay.
When you think about it, it was my fault.
So where to first?
…で どっから回りゃいいんだ？
ﾊﾟｯﾊﾟと回って終わらせようぜ！
Let's do this quickly so we can get it over with.
あぁ！ 風が気持いい!!
お～い 聞いてるのか？
The wind feels so good!!
Try and stop me!!
Hey, you listening?
Somebody just try and stop me!!
誰か私を止められるものなら
止めてみろ！
うがっ！
What the hell are you doing?!
何してんだ!? お前!!
ﾊﾞｶだろ！ お前 ﾊﾞｶだろ!!
You're an idiot.
A complete idiot.
早く乗れ！ こっちだ！
Hurry up and get on. This side!
あっ！
うわぁ～!! 止まらないで！
Don't stop! Don't stop!
止まらないで～!!
これは ﾑﾘ… これは ﾑﾘだ！
I can't help it. There's nothing I can do.
しばらく我慢しろ！ すぐだから!!
Just hang in there. We'll be going soon, okay?
Soon?
すぐだからっても もうﾀﾞﾒ…｡
我慢できませ～ん!!
No! I can't take it anymore!
I can't stand it!
Hey... Watch out...
(２人)うわぁ～!!
ｷｬﾊﾊﾊ！ 坂田さん すごいです！
This is amazing, Sakata-san!
風！ 私たち 風になってます!!
The wind! We've become the wind!
W-Wait. No... Time out!
ﾀﾝﾏ！ いったんﾀﾝﾏ！
下りるわ！ もうｵﾚ下ります！
I have to get off.  Please let me get off.
認識が甘かった～!!
I so did not see this coming!
何言ってるんですか！ まだ１軒も
配達してないじゃないですか！
What do you mean?!
We still haven't even made a single delivery!
I know. We haven't made a single delivery and things are already completely out of control!
１軒も配達してないのに
すでに こんな目に遭ってるから➡
言ってるんだろうが！
こんなもん あれだよ！
It's like that movie where the teacher tells the students
[Note: Spoof of "Battle Royale"]
入学式で いきなり先生に➡
to kill each other at their school entrance ceremony!
皆さんには 殺し合いを
してもらいます このﾔﾛｳ とか➡
言われてるようなもんだよ！
止まることもできねえのに➡
Besides, how are you going to deliver the parcels if you can't even stop?!
どうやって荷物を届けるつもり!?
よいしょっ！
Here we go.
んっ!?
(悲鳴)
One down. Next is...
１軒目終了｡ 次はと…｡
これは 配達というんですか？
ﾃﾛと いうんじゃないですか？
You call that delivery?
I call it terrorism.
(全蔵)おっせぇな 飛脚｡
The messenger...is late.
(全蔵)確かに
今日 届くはずなんだが｡
I'm pretty sure it was supposed to come today.
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣応募者全員ｻｰﾋﾞｽ｡
My O-Edo squadron GinTaman action figure set, the JUMP free subscription gift.
『大江戸戦隊ｷﾞﾝﾀﾏﾝ』ﾌｨｷﾞｭｱｾｯﾄ｡
(全蔵)あれ どうせ
すぐ打ち切りになるから➡
It's only while supplies last so if I don't get it now then I'll never...
今のうちに手に入れないと
二度と…｡
(のり子)ｷｬﾎｰ！
あれ？ 何だ このｶﾞﾗｸﾀ…｡
Huh? What's all this junk...?
So what do you want from me now?
(長谷川)どういう
風の吹き回しだ？
Calling me like this...
(長谷川)今さら
電話なんかしてきやがって…｡
You and I have been over for a long time.
ｵﾚたちは とっくに
終わったはずだ｡
You don't have to say it like that.
☎(ﾊﾂ)そんな言い方
しなくてもいいでしょ｡
I just called because I was worried you weren't eating right...
(ﾊﾂ)こっちはね ちゃんと ご飯
食べてるかとか心配して電話…｡
☎(長谷川)家出てったﾔﾂに
心配されたくねえよ！ 切るぞ｡
I don't need to have someone who walked out on me worry about me.
I'm hanging up.
(ﾊﾂ)ちょっと待って！
Wait!
Dear...
ｱﾝﾀ 今日が何の日か…
いや やっぱりいいわ｡
Do you know what today is...?
Oh no, never mind.
[TEL](長谷川)用もねえのに
電話してくんじゃねえよ｡
If you have no business with me, don't call.
[TEL](長谷川)じゃあな｡
Bye.
(電話が切れる音)
《ﾊﾂ:憶えてるわけないか…
結婚記念日なんて｡
Why would he remember...
...that today is our wedding anniversary?
何やってるんだろう 私
勝手に出ていっておいて…》
What am I doing?
I'm the one who walked out on him...
(のり子)すみませ～ん 飛脚です！
Excuse me! Delivery service!
《ﾊﾂ:まさか あの人…！》
Impossible! Could it be...?
《長谷川:ﾊﾂよ…｡
Hatsu...
[Happy Anniversary]
結婚10周年に乾杯…》
Here's to our tenth wedding anniversary.
どうだ？ ひととおり
さばいたんじゃねえか？
So what do you think? We're almost done, right?
すごいです！
残すところ あと１つですよ！
Great! Only one package left.
我ながら よくやったもんだよ｡
If I may say so myself, we did a pretty good job.
多少 届けもんが
傷んでもしゃあねえよ これは｡
We can't help it if some of the parcels were damaged.
よくやったよ｡
(ｻｲﾚﾝ)
Yeah, we did a good job.
(沖田)そこの暴走車
ただちに止まりなさい！
You in the speeding scooter!
Stop immediately!
Shut up!
うるせえぇ！ 止まれるもんなら
とっくに止まってんだよ！
If I could stop, I would've done it a long time ago!
私たちは 風になるんです！
We're going to become the wind.
(沖田)あれ？ 旦那じゃねえかぃ｡
何やってんで？ ﾃﾞｰﾄかい？
Huh? Hey Master Gin, what's up?
You on a date?
ｵﾒｴか！ おい ちょっと
まいってんだ｡ 助け…｡
Oh, it's you.
I'm in a bit of trouble here!
おい ｵﾚのなじみだ 退くぜぃ｡
Help...
Hey, he's a friend of mine.
Let him go.
ちょ… 待てよ！ 助けてって！
ああ 旦那➡
W-Wait.  Help me.
Oh yeah, Master, this delivery date of yours looks like fun, but be careful, okay?
飛脚ﾃﾞｰﾄも結構ですけどね
気をつけてくだせぃ｡
最近 攘夷志士の間で 妙な
破壊活動が流行ってましてね｡
Lately, there's been some terrorist activity by the exclusionist rebels.
こいつが 飛脚を使った
爆破事件でしてね➡
They have been using messengers to deliver their bombs.
何も知らねえ飛脚に
爆弾 運ばせて➡
They have this vicious scheme where they make
大使館だ 何だと狙う
悪どいやり方でね｡
innocent messengers deliver bombs to embassies and such.
まぁ 旦那も
気をつけてくだせえや ほいじゃ｡
So be careful, okay?
See'ya.
のり子ちゃん その最後の
届け物って あて先は…｡
Noriko, where does that last parcel go to?
大使館ですね｡
なんか変な音とかする？
The embassy.
Is it making weird noises?
ｶﾁｶﾁいってます 時計みたい｡
そう…｡
It's ticking. Like a clock.
I see...
ああ～っ！
Hey, Sakata-san, what are you doing?
何やってるんですか 坂田さん！
止まったら 私 死んじゃいます！
If we stop, I'll die!
We're gonna die anyway!
このままでも死ぬから！
爆弾だ それ爆弾だよぉ！
It's a bomb.
That's a bomb!
ちょ… 一旦 止まろう！
ちょっとだけ止まろう！
Let's just pull over for a second.
We'll just stop for a bit.
ｵﾚが ﾊﾞｲｸから下りたら
すぐ走ればいいじゃん！
When I get off the scooter, start running, okay?
だから 止まったら 私
死んじゃうんです！
I'm telling you, if we stop, I'll die.
いや もう そんなん
どうでもいいから！
Who cares about that anymore?
ｵﾚのほうが お前より
死にたくないから！
I don't wanna die any more than you!
私だけ爆死させるつもりですか!?
ﾊﾟｰﾄﾅｰじゃないですか！
So you're going to let me blow up alone?
I thought we were partners!
一緒に風になるって
約束したじゃないですか！
Didn't you promise me we'd become the wind together?
するか ﾎﾞｹ！ あれだよ お前➡
Like hell I did, you fool!
I hear when people die they become the wind anyways.
人間は死ぬと
風になれるらしいから➡
一旦 止まろう！
ｲﾔです！
So let's pull over!
No!
爆風は ｲﾔです！
爽やかな風がいいんです！
I don't want it to be an explosive blast.
I prefer a refreshing breeze!
(折れる音)
It came off!
もげたぁ！ ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ もげたぞ！
The brake broke off!!
Hey!  The handle!
あんのｼﾞｼﾞｲ どんだけ
適当な修理してんだぁ！
Damn old man, talk about a half-ass repair job.
[無線](源外)銀の字 銀の字
応答 願います｡
Gin, Gin.
Come in please.
[無線]こちら 源外だ｡ 応答 願います｡
無線!?
This is Gengai.
Come in please.
A radio?
[無線](源外)調子おかしいな…｡
It doesn't seem to be working.
I can't hear you so I'm gonna keep talking.
[無線]そっちの声は聞こえんから
一方的にしゃべるぞ！
あのｼﾞｼﾞｲ こんなもん
つける暇があるなら➡
That old geezer... If he had the time to install this, then he should've fixed the damn brakes!
ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ ちゃんと直しとけや！
[無線]ｵﾒｴに１つ
忠告するのを忘れてた｡
I forgot to warn you about something.
[無線]無線なんか
つけてる暇があるなら➡
I should've fixed the brakes instead of installing that radio.
ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ ちゃんと
直しとけばよかった… 以上｡
ただの懺悔じゃねえか！
That's all.
It's just a confession!
なに くだらねえことに
無線 使ってんの！
Don't use the radio for stupid stuff like that!
Knowing you, I'm sure the brakes are already gone.
[無線]ｵﾒｴのことだから すでに
ﾌﾞﾚｰｷは亡き者になってると思う｡
[無線]そんときは 下のほうに
赤いﾎﾞﾀﾝがあるのが見えるか？
When that happens, you see a red button on the bottom?
[無線]そいつは 緊急用からくり
起動ｽｲｯﾁだ｡ 押すと…｡
That's an emergency mechanism activation switch.
If you push it...
[無線]ﾛｹｯﾄﾌﾞｰｽﾀｰが起動して
飛躍的に加速する｡
The rocket booster will kick in and give you a dramatic burst of speed.
[無線]絶対に今は押すな｡
どんな文法の使い方!?
So whatever you do, don't push it.
You could've said that part first!!
ｷｬﾊﾊ… 風よ！
喜んでる場合か！
The wind!
This is no time to be excited!
We're the wind!
もう下りられねえじゃねえか！
どうすんだ これ どうすんだ ｵﾚ！
I'll never be able to get off now!
What should I do?
んげぇぇ！ 大江戸名物交通渋滞!?
Edo's specialty, the traffic jam!
もう お終いか!?
Is this how it ends?
Gin...
[無線]銀の字 ｵﾒｴのことだから
早とちりして➡
Knowing you, you've screwed the pooch and activated the rocket booster.
ﾛｹｯﾄﾌﾞｰｽﾀｰを稼動しちまう
こともあるだろう｡
[無線]そんときは
ﾒｰﾀｰの中に赤いﾎﾞﾀﾝが…｡
When that happens, there's a red button inside the speedometer case...
もう知るかぁ！
なるようになりやがれぇ！
Who the hell cares?!
Whatever happens, happens.
ｼﾞｼﾞｲ！ ﾃﾒｴ あの世で恨んで…｡
Old geezer!!
Damn it. I'll curse you from the afterlife!
(のり子)やったぁ！
坂田さん やりましたよ！
All right!!
Sakata-san, we did it!
飛んでる！
私たち 飛んでますよ！
We're flying!
ﾊﾊﾊ… あのｼﾞｼﾞｲ
やってくれるじゃねえか！
Not bad, old man... Not bad.
I'm the wind!
(のり子)これで安全なところまで
飛んで 爆弾を捨てられる！
Now we can fly somewhere safe and ditch the bomb.
私たち やりとげたんですよ！
We did it!!
ああ こんな
気持のいい風は初めて…｡
Oh gosh... This is the first time I've felt such a delicious breeze.
ありがとう 坂田さん｡ 私 正直➡
Thank you, Sakata-san.
To tell you the truth... I...didn't think I had the confidence to make it in Edo.
この江戸で やっていける
自信がなかったんです｡
でも 坂田さんのおかげで
自信とはいえないまでも➡
I may not have it yet, but thanks to you, I feel like I can succeed.
なんだか やる気が出てきました！
こんな私でも がむしゃらにやれば
何かをつかめるかもって…｡
Even someone like me can accomplish something if I work really hard.
そうかい 確かに
風ってのも悪かねえかも…｡
Is that so?
You may be right. The wind's not such a bad thing after all...
[無線](源外)銀の字 ｵﾒｴのことだ｡
Gin...
Knowing you, you haven't heeded any of my warnings and resorted to the flight feature.
[無線]人の話を聞かずに 最終兵器を
使うこともあるかもしれねえ｡
[無線]１つ言っておくが そいつは
えらくｴﾈﾙｷﾞｰを使う からくりだ｡
But let me warn you.
That mechanism uses up a lot of energy.
[無線]ｵﾒｴのﾊﾞｲｸじゃ 長時間 飛行を
続けるのは おそらく ﾑﾘだ｡
Your scooter won't be able to stay airborne for very long.
[無線]たぶん １分ぐらいで
爆発するから…｡
It'll probably explode in about a minute.
《のり子:東京都の斎藤さん…➡
Dear Saito-san of Tokyo.
いろいろ落ち込んだりも
するけれど➡
I do get depressed at times, but I'm doing well.
[Note: Spoof of "Kiki's Delivery Service".]
私は 元気にやっています｡
私… この街が好きです》
I love this town.
(さっちゃん)獲物は？
(胴元)大江戸病院医師➡
Who's the target?
Heihachiro Kuroda, a doctor at Oedo Hospital.
黒田 平八郎｡
[Dango Café]
Looks like he's involved in organ trafficking.
どうやら 臓器売買に
手をつけているようだ｡
ｲｷのいい患者を見つけては
腹を かっさばいて➡
He finds a healthy patient, slits them open and steals their organs.
臓器を取り出している 外道よ｡
He's a real devil.
外道…｡
A devil.
本当の外道は
人を始末し 金を得る➡
Real devils are people like us who kill other people for money.
私たちのことだわ｡
(胴元)ちげぇねえ｡
That's true.
(胴元)弱き民を救うため
また 外道になってくれるか？
Will you become a devil once again to save the weak?
Only devils can eliminate other devils.
(さっちゃん)外道にしか絶てぬ
外道というものがある｡
私が 汚れて
誰かが救われるというのなら➡
If I can save others, I'm happy to get a little blood on my hands.
喜んで この手 血に染めましょう｡
["The Ideal Girlfriend Is Always Minami"]
(胴元)ところで 一つ
聞きたいことがあるんだが｡
By the way, I want to ask you something.
お前さん 最近
いい人でもできたか？
Do you have a boyfriend right now?
Wh-what?
(さっちゃん)なっ… 何を…？
(胴元)いや 最近 お前さんから➡
It's just that you smell more like a woman these days.
女のにおいがして
ならねぇんでな｡
It's your imagination. What is this? Sexual harassment?
(さっちゃん)勘違いよ｡ ｾｸﾊﾗ｡
まぁ それなら いいんだが…｡
Whatever you say.
(胴元)ｵﾚも長年 お前らみたいな
連中と つきあってきたがね➡
I've been around people like you for a long time.
女ができた 所帯を持ったという
連中から 死んでいく｡
Those who are married or have girlfriends are the ones who end up dead first.
(胴元)人間に 情なんて
持ってるﾔﾂが やっていけるほど➡
Once you start developing any feelings for a person, this business will eat you alive.
[O-Edo Hospital]
この商売 甘かねえんだ｡
(胴元)お前さんも
一時の情にほだされて➡
Be careful your passions don't get the better of you. It could trip you up.  Be careful, okay?
足すくわれねえように
気をつけるこった｡
Gin-san, I'll be okay, right?
《さっちゃん:
銀さん 私は 大丈夫よね｡
だって 私の この感情は➡
After all, these feelings for you aren't some fleeting infatuation.
いっときのものなんかじゃ
ないもの｡
Lately, all I can think about is you.
だって 最近は 四六時中
銀さんのことばかり考えて➡
仕事も手につかないし
いっときのものなんかじゃないわ｡
I can't even concentrate on my work.
This is no schoolgirl crush.
大丈夫よ！ これは｡
I'll be fine.
あれ？ 大丈夫なのか？ これ｡
Huh? Is it really okay?
No, it's okay.
あ… いや 大丈夫よ｡
The important thing is knowing when to turn it on and off.
大切なのは 切り替えよ！
仕事をやるときは死ぬ気で仕事を｡
When I work, I'll work to death.
恋をするときは 死ぬ気で恋を｡
And when I love, I'll love to death.
That kind of attitude will enrich my life.
そういう姿勢が
生活を豊かにするのよ》
Hey, newbie!
(ﾅｰｽ長)おい 新入り！ 病院では
ｹｰﾀｲの電源切っとくのが➡
It's common sense to turn your cell phone off in the hospital!
常識だろうが！
ﾊﾞｶか ﾃﾒｴは！
Are you stupid?
ﾃﾒｴの電源 切ったろか！
(さっちゃん)すみません ﾅｰｽ長！
Turn it off before I turn you off, okay?!
I'm sorry, Head Nurse!!
That's right. It's time to turn off "Sachan the lovestruck pig."
《そう… 今は
ﾒｽ豚さっちゃんﾓｰﾄﾞは ｵﾌよ｡
始末屋さっちゃんﾓｰﾄﾞを ｵﾝに》
And turn on "Sachan the killer".
(医師)坂田さん ｱﾝﾀ いったい
何回 入院するの？ 今度は なに？
Sakata-san, how many times have you been hospitalized already?
What is it this time?
ﾊﾞｲｸが 爆発して
地上30ｍから 川に落下しました｡
My scooter exploded and I fell 30 meters into a river.
(医師)ﾊﾞｶは
死んでも治らんというけど➡
They say only death can cure stupidity, but you sure won't die, huh?
ｱﾝﾀは まだ 死なないね｡
先生～！
Doctor, isn't a doctor's job to care for both the patient's body and mind?
医者の仕事は
患者を 心身ともに➡
ｹｱすることなんじゃないっすか？
心も 体も ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛです！
Mine are both in shreds.
《ﾒｽ豚ﾓｰﾄﾞ ｵﾝ！》
"Lovestruck Pig" mode.
On!
銀さ～ん！
ぎゃふんっ！
Gin-san!!
ｷﾞｬｱ！ 足踏んでる
足踏んでる！ 足踏んでる!!
You're on my legs! You're on my legs!
You're stepping on my legs!
Gin-san, why? This is...terrible!
(さっちゃん)銀さん
どうしてこんな… ひどい…｡
What happened? Are you okay?
いったい 何があったの？
大丈夫なの？
Doctor, he's okay, right?
先生！ 大丈夫ですよね？
これ 銀さん 大丈夫なんですよね｡
Gin-san is going to be okay, right?
治りますよね？ 頭！
頭のことか～い!!
You'll fix it, right?
His hair!
So all you care about is the hair?!
This condition is called "Comedic Post-Explosion Hair".
これはね
ﾄﾞﾘﾌ爆発後ﾍｱｰといって➡
２～３ｶｯﾄたてば 何も
なかったように 元に戻るから➡
After two or three scenes, it should return to normal like nothing ever happened, so don't worry.
安心しなさい｡
(さっちゃん)ｲﾔです｡
No!  I want you to fix it in this scene.
(さっちゃん)このｶｯﾄで
すぐ 治してください！
Who cares about that?
どうでもいいから 仕事しろ
新入り！ お前の担当は こっち！
Get back to work, newbie!
Your patient's over here!
はい 薬の時間ですよ｡ ほら 早く
猿飛さん 薬ぬってあげて！
Okay, time for your medication.
Come on, Sarutobi-san, rub the medicine on him.
(全蔵)あ すみません
お願いします｡
Oh, thank you.
It's been killing me since yesterday and I can't stand it...
もう 昨日から 痛くて 痛くて
しかたないんですよ… 痔｡
My hemorrhoids.
"Killer" mode, on!
(さっちゃん)始末屋ﾓｰﾄﾞ ｵﾝ！
So what are you doing here?
で？ なんで お前が
こんなところに いんだ？
どういうことだ？ これは？
What's going on?
(さっちゃん)私のことが
知りたいの ぼうや｡
You want to know about me, little boy?
Then you can't rush it.
だったら あせったら ﾀﾞﾒ｡
女を知りたいなら じっくり➡
If you want to get to know a woman, take your time.
そして 優しく 一枚いちまい…｡
あぁ じゃあ もういいわ｡
Gently, one layer at a time...
Oh, never mind then.
いや… あの…
もうちょっと 続きあんだけど…｡
Well, I wasn't quite finished yet.
いや もういいって｡
めんどくせぇから｡
Don't bother. It's too much trouble
《何やってるのかしら 私｡
What am I doing?
I said the important thing is knowing when to turn it on and off,
気持の切り替えが 大事とか
言っておきながら➡
銀さんを前にしたら
ただの ﾒｽ豚になってしまう｡
but when Gin-san's in front of me, I just go on auto-pig.
I must quickly switch over to "Killer" mode.
早く 始末屋ﾓｰﾄﾞに切り替えるのよ｡
Now that I think about it, what's so great about this guy anyway?
考えたら こんな男の
どこがいいのよ｡
I like sadistic men who'll brutally ravish me.
私は ｶﾞﾝｶﾞﾝ攻めてくる
Ｓな男が好きなの｡
こんな弱った 銀さんなんて…｡
Who wants a sissy Gin-san that's so...
Weak...
弱っ… そういえば
男は 弱っているときに➡
Come to think of it,
優しくされると ｺﾛｯていくって
脇さんが 前に言ってたわ｡
Waki-san told me that men can't resist girls who are nice to them when they're down.
あと 『ﾀｯﾁ』の南ちゃんにも
弱いって言ってた｡
She also told me they have a weakness for Minami-chan from Touch.
[Note: Touch is a manga by Mitsuru Adachi. Minami was one of the main female characters]
"Lovestruck Pig" mode, on!
ﾒｽ豚ﾓｰﾄﾞ ｵﾝ！》
Oh come on, Gi-chan. You're always so grumpy.
もう ぎっちゃんたら！ いっつも
そんな無愛想なんだから！
あ？
そんなんじゃ さっちゃん➡
If you keep acting like that, I might leave you for another man, okay?
違う人のところに行っちゃうぞ！
どこにでも 行けよ！
Go wherever you want.
And while you're out, go buy me JUMP from the store downstairs.
あぁ ついでに 売店で
｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣買ってきて｡
I might go to Moscow, okay?
ﾓｽｸﾜに行っちゃうぞ！
南ちゃんなのに北に行っちゃうぞ｡
I may be Minami-chan, but I may even go north, okay?
[Note: In Japanese, Minami also means south.]
I don't think they sell JUMP in Moscow.
ﾓｽｸﾜに ｢ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟ｣売ってねえだろ！
実は～➡
Actually, I figured hospital food doesn't taste very good...
病院のごはん
おいしくないと思って 南…➡
Minami... I mean, Sachan brought you some homemade food.
じゃねえや… さっちゃん
手料理を作ってきたのでした！
You want some?
食べたい？ どうしよっかな～？
あげよっかな～？
Oh, what should I do? Should I give you some?
なんか わかんないけど
ぶっ飛ばしたいんだけど ｺｲﾂ！
I'm not sure why, but I feel like punching her lights out.
じゃあ～ん！ なんと
おでんなのでした！
Ta-da!
Can you believe, it's oden!
[Note: Oden is a Japanese Winter dish made from boiled eggs, daikon, konjac gel, fish cakes and other ingredients stewed in a pot.]
Ah, hot, hot!
ｱﾁｬﾁｬﾁｬﾁｬｲ！
Why would you bring a pot of boiling hot oden to someone who can't move?
なんで よりによって
動けねえときに ｱﾂｱﾂのおでん？
それも がんも!?
家庭的な味に➡
And is that deep-fried tofu?
I thought you would be starved for some home cooking, okay?
飢えてると思ったんだｿﾞ！
｢ｿﾞ｣の使い方が➡
Do you have to keep saying "Okay"?
おかしくなってきてんぞ！
他の患者さんには 内緒だｿﾞ！
Don't tell the other patients, okay?
あぁ 見～ちゃった！
Oh man, I saw everything.
Maybe I'll tell the head nurse?
ﾅｰｽ長に 言っちゃおうかな？
(さっちゃん)それじゃ ぎっちゃん
ちょっと 横になってくれる？
Okay, Gi-chan, lie down for a second now, okay?
包帯を 新しいのに替えるんだｿﾞ！
I'm going to change your bandages, okay?
It's okay.
いいって！
さっき やってもらったから！
I just had them changed.
Oh, come on. Don't be shy, okay?
(さっちゃん)
照れなくてもいいんだｿﾞ！
I told you, it's okay.
いいって言ってんだろ！
あっ ｲﾃﾃﾃﾃ！
Ouch, ouch, ouch.
Oh stop, Gi-chan. Don't move, okay?
(さっちゃん)あん もう！
ぎっちゃん 動かないでｿﾞ！
See? You moved...
んもう！ ぎっちゃんが動くから！
...so look what happened, okay?
こんなんなっちまったｿﾞ！
どう
動いたら そんなことになんだ！
How exactly could I be responsible for that?
You tied that bondage harness yourself? Amazing, isn't it?
っていうか 自分で縛ったの？
それ！ すごくねぇ？
I like that part of you that refuses to be tied down, okay?
さっちゃんは ぎっちゃんの
そういう 何者にも➡
縛られないところ
結構 好きだｿﾞ！
でも やっぱり ｹｶﾞが心配だから…｡
あっ ｲﾀﾀﾀﾀﾀ！
But I am worried about your injuries...
Ouch, ouch, ouch.
...so I should tie you up, okay?
ちゃんと 縛るんだｿﾞ！
何しやがるんだ！
What the hell are you doing?
ﾅｰｽ長！ 助けてくれ！
あっ ｲﾀﾀﾀﾀ！
Head Nurse!  Help me!
うぅ… 待ってろ！
今すぐ ﾅｰｽ長を！
Hang on.
I'll call the head nurse right now...
(さっちゃん)それじゃ 私
ちょっと 売店 行ってくるけど➡
I'm going to go to the gift shop now.
なんだっけ？
｢ｻﾝﾃﾞｰ｣買ってくればいいのよね！
What was it, now?
You wanted me to buy Sunday, right?
じゃ！ 待っててｿﾞ～！
I'll be right back, okay?
Have you ever heard of the movie, "Misery?"
お前さぁ…
『ﾐｻﾞﾘｰ』っていう映画 知ってる？
ｹｶﾞして動けない作家が➡
The injured author who can't move
看病と称して
ﾎﾞｯｺﾎﾞｺにされるやつ…｡
gets crippled by the psychotic caretaker who is supposedly there to take care of him.
Man, that was really scary.
あれ 怖かったよなぁ！
おばちゃんの演技がｽｺﾞくって…｡
That lady actress was so believable.
W-Wait a sec!
(全蔵)ちょ ちょっ 待ってくれ！
これ… ﾛｳｿｸ抜いてくれ！
Pull the candle out!
ﾃﾒｴで抜けや！ なんでｵﾚが！
You pull it out.
Why should I do it?
(全蔵)ﾀﾞﾒだ！ 痛くて
抜いたら 何か大切な物も➡
I can't do it.
It's so painful. If I do it, I'm afraid something important will come out with it!
抜けてってしまいそうな
気がするぅ！
You keeping your hopes and dreams in there?
ｵﾒｴは肛門に 夢や希望までも
詰まってるのかぁっ!?
(神楽)銀ちゃ～んっ！
元気にしてるｱﾙか!?
Gin-chan!
How are you doing?
(新八)お見舞いに来ましたよ！
We've come to cheer you up!!
…えっ!?
Gin-chan, you idiot!
銀ちゃんのﾊﾞｶ～!!
Oh man, our bad.
いや～ 悪かったな！
神楽ちゃんには➡
I'll explain that kind of thing to Kagura-chan.
そういう世界があることも
伝えとくから！
No, wait! It's not what you think!
ちょっと待て～！ 違うから！
そういうんじゃねえって！
I'm not into stuff like that!!
そういう世界って何？
どういう世界!?
What "things"?!
What am I gonna do now?
どうしてくれんだよ お前!!
家 帰って 説明しても➡
Even if I explain it when I get home, it's still gonna be really awkward.
絶対なんか ﾌﾜﾌﾜﾌ～した感じに
なっちまうよ！
悪かったな！
ｵﾚも一緒に行って説明するわ｡
Sorry about that.
I'll go with you and explain.
余計 怪しまれるから
来ないでくれっ！
Forget it! That'll be even more suspicious!
もう ｵﾚと同じｶｯﾄに立つな！
Just don't ever stand in the same scene as me again!
とにかく今は…｡
早く逃げねえと！
Well, whatever the case may be, right now...
We'd better get the hell outta here.
Well, well, if it isn't Sakata-san and Hattori-san.
(黒田)おやおや…
坂田さん 服部さん！
ﾀﾞﾒですよ！
ｹｶﾞ人が勝手に動いちゃ…｡
Patients aren't allowed to crawl about unsupervised.
《もうなんか… 仕事のこととか
どうでもよくなってきたわ！
This is so much more fun than my real job.
Women should live for love and not for work.
やっぱり女は 仕事より
愛に生きるべきなのよ！
Maybe I'll retire from this gory assassin job and really become a nurse.
始末屋なんて
血なまぐさい仕事は引退して➡
ﾎﾝﾄにﾅｰｽになろうかしら？
銀さんだけのﾅｰｽだけど…》
I'll just be Gin-san's exclusive personal nurse.
(ﾅｰｽ)聞いた？ 黒田先生が…｡
(ﾅｰｽ)ｱﾚ ﾎﾝﾄなの!?
Did you hear?
About Dr. Kuroda?
Is it really true?
I heard he's involved in organ trade.
臓器売買に手を出してるって
ｳﾜｻ…｡
それで こないだから入院してる
うるさい人たち いるじゃない？
Yeah, and you know those noisy patients in the hospital right now?
ああ！ 坂田さんと服部さん？
Oh yeah, you mean Sakata-san and Hattori-san.
(ﾅｰｽ)次は どうもｱｲﾂらが
目つけられてるらしいわよ｡
Well apparently, they're his next targets.
(ﾅｰｽ)ああ… そりゃ 静かになって
いいんじゃない！
That's not so bad. It'll sure be a lot quieter around here.
Oh my God! Gin-san!
《そんな！ 銀さんが…》
(ﾅｰｽ)ちょっとｱﾝﾀ！
Hey, you!
It's all my fault!
《私のせいだわ！
私が仕事をなまけて…》
It's because I was slacking on the job!
((一時の情にほだされて➡
Be careful your passions don't get the better of you.
It could trip you up. Be careful, okay?
足 すくわれねえように
気をつけるこった…))
What am I doing?
《何やってるの 私！
All this foolish talk about love and being in love...
愛だの恋だの
くだらないことばかり言って…》
We've done a complete medical workup on both of you
実は全身 検査させて
もらったんだけどね➡
and found severe internal problems.
ｷﾐたちの体の中は
もう ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛなわけ｡
(黒田)坂田さん あなた日頃から
糖尿の気があるのに➡
Sakata-san, you're at high risk for diabetes yet you continue to eat sweets.
以前と変わらず
甘いものを摂り続けている｡
ああ… もう
そのへん 割り切ってるんで｡
Oh yeah, I've gotten to the point where
I've decided that I'll live a thick, rich, creamy life, however short.
好きなもの食って
太く短く生きるって…｡
これ見て｡
もう
いいですって！ ﾋﾞﾋﾞんないすよ｡
Take a look at this.
Never mind already. It's not gonna scare me.
ｵﾚ そういうの言われ慣れてるから
ﾋﾞﾋﾞんないっすよ！
I'm used to hearing stuff like that. You can't scare me one bit.
(黒田)このままいったらね
糖と尿が 超反応起こして➡
If this keeps up, the sugar and urine in your body will become a deadly mix
睾丸が爆発します｡
and your testicles will explode.
No way!
There's...nothing I can do to protect him?
《私 何も守ることができないの？
いちばん大切なものも
守れないっていうの？》
Don't tell me I can't even protect the one I care about the most.
(黒田)で 服部さん…
あなた痔を➡
And as for you, Hattori-san.
It seems you came here to treat your hemorrhoids.
本格的に
治しにきたみたいだけど…｡
はい… 恥ずかしいけど
がんばろうと思います｡
Yes, as embarrassing as it is, I'll do my best.
それなんだけどね…➡
Well, about that...
このままいったら
なんか爆発します｡
At the rate you're going...
Something...will explode.
《ｵﾚのほう… 適当じゃねえ!?》
That's kinda random, isn't it?
《全蔵は どうでもいい！》
I don't care about Zenzo.
ああっ！
《これじゃ 私…➡
God, I really am a totally useless...
まるで本当に…
何もできない ﾀﾀﾞの➡
ﾒｽ豚じゃない！
...lovestruck pig.
Just a plain ol' lovestruck pig.
こんなのﾀﾀﾞのﾒｽ豚…｡
じゃない！ ﾒｽ豚なんかじゃ…｡
That's not true...
I'm not a lovestruck pig...
私は ﾒｽ豚なんかじゃない！
I'm not...a lovestruck pig...
私は… 私は…➡
I'm...
I'M!
始末屋ﾓｰﾄﾞ ｵﾝ！》
Killer mode, ON!
(黒田)ﾌﾌﾌｯ… ﾊﾞｶどもめ！
What fools.
あんな説明にﾀﾞﾏされるとは
ﾎﾝﾄ ﾊﾞｶ！
To believe a load of crap like that...
What imbeciles!
(黒田)あの調子じゃ
脳は使いものにならんが➡
At this rate, your brains are totally useless.
But the other organs are exceptional.
その他は 実にすばらしい！
It'll be better for the world if we give them to people who can put them to good use.
もっと有効に活用してくれる人に
譲るのが➡
世の中のためってもんだ！
ﾊﾊﾊﾊﾊ…｡
では 始めよう｡ 用意はできたか？
はい！
Let's begin.
Is everything ready?
Yes.
ﾒｽ｡
はい！
Scalpel.
Yes.
ｷﾞｬｰｯ！ 何しての!?
(助手)先生！
Wh...What do you think you're doing?
Doctor!!
ｷﾐ… いったい何してるんだ!?
You!!  What the hell are you doing?
I'm sorry.  I dropped my glasses.
すみません｡
ﾒｶﾞﾈ落としちゃって…｡
So I tend to confuse the words "Scalpel" and "Shank".
もう ﾒｽだか ｵｽだか ﾄﾞｽだか…
わからなくなっちゃって｡
You bitch!
ｷｻﾏ！ 何者だ!?
Who the hell are you?
(さっちゃん)祇園精舎の鐘の声｡
諸行無常の響きあり｡
The bells of Gion Temple ring for you...
"All is vanity" toll the bells....
[Note: A famous opening passage from the historical novel, "Tale of Heike".]
Wh-What the heck is this?
(さっちゃん)沙羅双樹の花の色｡
The brutal devil...
Bandages?
ぐわぁっ！
ぬぉぉっ！
鬼畜外道！
必殺の理をあらはす｡
...delivers a righteous deathblow.
お大事に…｡
Take care.
始末屋さっちゃん！ 見参！
Assassin Sachan...has arrived!!
Gin-san!! Gin-san...
銀さん！ 銀さん どこなの？
無事なの？
Where are you?
Are you all right?
Gin-san!!
銀さ～ん！
Thank goodness!
(さっちゃん)よかったぁ！
I can't see anything without my glasses, but you're okay, right?
ﾒｶﾞﾈがなくて 何も見えないけど
無事なのよね？
(さっちゃん)ごめんなさい…
全部 私のせいなの｡
I'm sorry...
It's all my fault...
私… 男にうつつなんて
抜かしてるﾔﾂが➡
I...was warned that love would interfere with my work.
仕事なんて できるわけないって
言われて➡
But I still couldn't get you out of my mind, Gin-san.
でも やっぱり銀さんのこと
忘れられなくて…｡
でも 私 想うの…
守るものが 何もない人より➡
But this is what I think...
An assassin who has someone she wants to protect
誰か 大切な人がいるほうが➡
守るために力を
発揮できるんじゃないかって…｡
is more motivated than one who has no one.
だから私 今までと変わらず➡
That's why, I won't change my ways...
And I'll always...
これからも
ずっと銀さんのこと…｡
...keep thinking of you, Gin-san...
…あれ!?
(いびき)
Huh?
(ｵﾅﾗの音)
《始末屋ﾓｰﾄﾞ ｵﾝ！》
Killer mode, on!
(全蔵)ぎゃぁぁぁぁぁっ!!
The next episode, summer ghost stories...
"Like a Haunted House, Life is Filled with Horrors."
[This year's ghosts will be done by Odd Jobs. It will be thrilling in many ways.]
[This is Ochi-san, who will risk his life, at the summer festival's Haunted House.]